Tomie dePaola Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
- Series III: Art Work, undated, 1949-1999
  - “A Bestiary” (6 drawings) -rubber stamp, pen & ink, watercolor on Reeves BFK paper, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
  - “Old Woman” -pencil on paper, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
  - “6 B's” (8 drawings) -inks & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
  - “Fortune Telling Lady” -pen & ink & tempera on illustration board, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
  - “Trees” -colored inks on illustration board, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 64)
  - “Moon” -colored inks on illustration board, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 65)
  - “Moon and Sea” -colored inks on illustration board, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 66)
  - “4 Saints in 3 Acts” -rubber stamp, pencil & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 67)
  - “Virgos Unite” -rubber stamps and colored inks on board, c. 1960s (Box 2:, Folder 68)
  - “Amphora and Plinth” - acrylic on board, ca. 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 69)
  - “Dido and Aneaus” -silkscreen, 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 70)
  - Bird drawings (2) -pencil & tempera on paper, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 71)
  - “Jungian symbol” -acrylic on board, ca. 1967-1970 (Box 2:, Folder 72)
  - Poster for Monster's Ball play, -silkscreen, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 73)
  - Still life of Tomie's desk -pen & ink on paper, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 3:, Folder 74)
  - Garden w/ rabbit and man -pencil & watercolor, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 75)
  - “Sister Angelica” -pen & ink on paper, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 76)
  - “Two men & gazebo” -pen & ink on paper, ca. late 1950s (Box 3:, Folder 77)
  - “Three Kings” -tempera on board, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 3:, Folder 78)
  - “Nude with Mandala” -ink & watercolor, 1970 (Box 3:, Folder 79)
  - St. Benedict - ink wash on paper, ca. 1960s (Box 3:, Folder 80)
  - Sketch of “Dad” -ink on paper, ca. 1968 (Box 3:, Folder 81)
  - “Baby” -ink on paper, ca. 1960s (Box 3:, Folder 82)
  - “Hearts” -ink on paper, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 83)
  - “Wedding” -ink on paper, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 84)
  - “Love” -inks on paper, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 85)
  - “Virgin and House” -inks on paper, 1969 (Box 3:, Folder 86)
  - “Bravo B's” 2 sketches -ink on paper, undated (Box 3:, Folder 87)
  - “Sun designs” -pen & ink on paper, 1960 (Box 3:, Folder 88)
  - “Grace Coolidge” -inks on paper, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 89)
  - “Hedda Gabler” -pen & ink & watercolor on paper, ca. 1968-1969 (Box 3:, Folder 90)
  - “Bravo B's” -tempera on paper, 1969 (Box 3:, Folder 91)
  - “Birds Pulling Reliquary” -ink & watercolor, 1969 (Box 3:, Folder 92)
  - “Expulsion from the Garden” -tempera on board, 1964 (Box 3:, Folder 93)
  - “Rainbow” & “Palm tree” (2 on one matte) -pencil & watercolor on board, 1968 (Box 3:, Folder 94)
  - “Jesus Walks on Water” -tempera on board, 1964 (Box 3:, Folder 95)
  - “Woman and Cat” -pen & inks on board, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 96)
  - “Deus” -ink and crayon on paper, ca. 1960 (Box 3:, Folder 97)
  - 3 Illustrations, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 98)
    - - Black spot -ink on paper
    - - Study for red drawings -ink wash
    - - Woman -pen & ink & ink wash on paper
  - 3 Illustrations -ink on paper, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 99)
    - - “RIP”
    - - “Hearts”
    - - “Sun”
  - 3 Illustrations -ink on paper, 1967 (Box 3:, Folder 100)
    - - “Hearts”
    - - “Heart Machine”
    - - “Wow”
  - 4 Illustrations (Box 3:, Folder 101)
    - - “Saint Placid” -pen & ink on paper, 1961
    - - “Two Boys” -pen & ink on paper, 1960
    - - “Crossroads” -pen & ink on paper, 1960
    - - “Little Milkmaid” -pen & watercolor on paper, 1961
  - “Portrait of a Lady” -wash out on board, 1955 (Box 3:, Folder 102)
  - “You can never find a troll when you need one” - pencil & watercolor on paper, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 103)
  - “Postcard from Monica and a bullseye” -pencil and watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 3:, Folder 104)
  - “You will find a family of unicorns...” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1976 (Box 3:, Folder 105)
  - “Crocus Sitting on a Faded...” -pencil & watercolor, 1985 (Box 3:, Folder 106A)
  - “Still Life Number One” -pencil & watercolor, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 106B)
  - “Still Life Number Four” -pencil & watercolor, 1975 (Box 3:, Folder 106C)
  - “Ophelia as she floated...” -pencil & watercolor, 1972 (Box 3:, Folder 106D)
  - “Fortune is like glass...” -colored inks, Scholastic Art Awards Entry, ca. 1951-1952 (Box 3:, Folder 106E)
  - “Kiss a Bird Day” -pencil, watercolor, tempera & rubber stamp on paper, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 106F)
  - “Moon Juggler” -pen & colored inks on board, 1968 (Box 4:, Folder 106)
  - “The Tree by Living Waters” -marker on paper, undated (Box 4:, Folder 107)
  - “The Thunder being brave...” -pencil & watercolor, 1972 (Box 4:, Folder 107A)
  - Mother & Child -pen & ink on paper, 1953 (Box 4:, Folder 107B)
  - Crucifixion -tempera & watercolor on paper, ca. 1960 (Box 4:, Folder 107C)
  - Girl & Bird -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 4:, Folder 107D)
  - “The Princess Avalina and...” -pencil & watercolor, 1972 (Box 4:, Folder 107E)
  - Wedding Drawing -watercolor on blotter paper, 1969 (Box 4:, Folder 107F)
  - “Woman on Columns” -watercolor, pen & ink, 1969 (Box 4:, Folder 108)
  - “Angel” -pencil, crayon & black ink on paper, 1983 (Box 4:, Folder 109)
  - St Veronica - tempera on board, 1956 (Box 4:, Folder 110)
  - St Benedict - wash out on illustration board, 1956 (Box 4:, Folder 111)
  - “EAT!” -pencil, pen & ink, watercolor & rubber stamp on paper, 1968 (Box 4:, Folder 112)
  - “The Brothers” -pen & ink, wash on board, 1961 (Box 4:, Folder 113)
  - “Bluebeard” -acrylic on board, 1973 (Box 4:, Folder 114)
  - “Hippie Girl” -colored inks on board, ca. 1970-71 (Box 4:, Folder 115)
  - “The Fog Maiden” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1975 (Box 4:, Folder 116)
  - “It is known in Altheria...” -brown pencil & watercolor on paper, 1976 (Box 4:, Folder 117)
  - Book Related Material
    - “Pierrot” -marker, watercolor, rubber stamp, & pen and ink on paper, 1968 (Box 5:, Folder 118)
    - “Pierrot was a baby once” -pencil & watercolor, 1978 (Box 5:, Folder 118A)
    - Sample agent for Sound - pen & ink & colored inks on illustration board, ca. 1960 (Box 5:, Folder 119)
    - Sample agent for The Reluctant Dragon - pen & ink, colored inks on illustration board, ca. 1960 (Box 5:, Folder 120)
    - “Mother Goose Boy” -ink & acrylic on paper, 1984 (Box 5:, Folder 121)
    - Peacock & bunny -study for Strega Nona -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1974 (Box 5:, Folder 122)
    - “Strega Nona's House” -pencil & watercolor, 1974 (Box 5:, Folder 123)
    - The Unicorn and the Moon -study for illustration, 1973 (Box 5:, Folder 124)
    - The Morning Glory - pen & ink illustrations 1, 4-12, undated (Box 5:, Folder 125A)
    - “Glimera, the Story of a Mermaid”, written for sister, Maureen, 1949 December (Box 5:, Folder 125B)
    - “The Sun and the Wind” -portfolio illustration for artists' rep. Pencil by Florence., ca. 1962-1963 (Box 5:, Folder 125C)
    - “This is to tell you...” etching prints for The Journey of the Kiss, undated (Box 5:, Folder 125D)
    - Etching prints: The Moon & the Kiss, Story plan for The Journey of the Kiss, undated (Box 5:, Folder 125E)
    - Etching proofs of The Journey of the Kiss - complete, 1969 (Box 5:, Folder 125F)
    - Etching proofs of The Journey of the Kiss -incomplete, 1969 (Box 5:, Folder 125G)
    - Illustration The Journey of the Kiss -pen & ink & watercolor, undated (Box 5:, Folder 125H)
  - Tomie dePaola: His Art & His Stories (Box 5A)
    - - Revised Master Proof, 1999 March 7 (Box 5A:, Folder 125I)
  - Strega Nona Meets Her Match
    - First draft- handwritten, 1992 January 31 (Box 5A:, Folder 125J)
    - First draft- typed, 1992 January 31 (Box 5A:, Folder 125K)
    - Edited manuscript, 1992 February 9 (Box 5A:, Folder 125L)
    - Galley, undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125M)
    - Jacket Specifications, undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125N)
    - Waxed Galley, 1992 March 12 (Box 5A:, Folder 125O)
    - Galley w/ editorial questions, 1992 March 12 (Box 5A:, Folder 125P)
    - Sketches (front & back), undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125Q)
    - Photocopy of sketch, undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125R)
    - Sketch & Jacket idea, undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125S)
    - Sketch for final jacket cover, undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125T)
    - Jacket proof, undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125U)
    - Faxed Galleys & request for dedication, 1992 July 16 (Box 5A:, Folder 125V)
    - Front flap draft (Faxed), 1992 July 20 (Box 5A:, Folder 125W)
    - Note from Patrick Collins w/ color samples & jacket proof, 1993 March 8 (Box 5A:, Folder 125X)
    - Color photocopies of artwork, undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125Y)
    - First proof of miniature edition, undated (Box 5A:, Folder 125Z)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5A:, Folder 126A)
  - Things to Do and Make for Valentine's Day (Box 5B)
    - Original Illustration, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126B)
  - Tomie dePaola's Book of Christmas Carols
    - (2) Original Illustrations, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126C)
  - Tomie dePaola's Kitten Kids
    - (4) Original Illustrations, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126D)
  - Baby's First Christmas
    - (2) Original Illustrations, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126E)
  - For Every Child A Star (Box 5B:, Folder 126F)
    - (3) Illustrations, undated
  - Teeny Tiny
    - (5) Illustrations, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126G)
  - Petook
    - (2) Illustrations, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126H)
  - Tomie dePaola's Favorite Nursery Tales
    - (23) Watercolor Illustrations, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126I)
  - My First Halloween
    - (3) Original Illustrations, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126J)
  - Merry Christmas, Strega Nona
    - Original Illustration, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126K)
  - Haircuts for the Woolseys
    - Original Illustration, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126L)
  - Erandi's Braids
    - Notes, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126M)
    - Color Photocopies of research photos, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126N)
    - (2) Manuscripts, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126O)
    - Sketch, (2) Watercolor Illustrations, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126P)
    - Photocopy of Illustration, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126Q)
    - Photocopy of Book-mock-up, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126R)
    - (2) Book mock-ups, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126S)
    - Book lay-out plan, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126T)
    - Book mock-up with original sketches, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126U)
    - First Color Proof, 1998 April 4 (Box 5B:, Folder 126V)
    - Cover & Endpaper notes, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126W)
    - Jacket flap notes, undated (Box 5B:, Folder 126X)
    - Jacket proofs, 1998 May 16 (Box 5B:, Folder 126Y)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 5B:, Folder 126Z)
  - Tomie dePaola's Make Your Own Christmas Cards
    - 1st Color Proofs, 1998 March 28 (Box 5B:, Folder 127)
    - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 5B:, Folder 127A)
  - The Prince of the Dolomites (Box 5C)
    - Original Illustration, undated (Box 5C:, Folder 127B)
  - The Night of Las Pasadas
    - Color Photocopies of Original Illustrations, undated (Box 5C:, Folder 127C)
    - 1st Color Proofs- including jacket, 1999 June 3 (Box 5C:, Folder 127D)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 5C:, Folder 127E)
  - Who's Afraid of the Water-Spurting Whale
    - (6) Original Illustrations & (17) Text Art, undated (Box 5C:, Folder 127F)
  - The Art Lesson
    - (6) Illustrations, undated (Box 5C:, Folder 127G)
  - Queen Esther
    - (3) Illustrations, undated (Box 5C:, Folder 127H)
  - The Parables of Jesus
    - (2) Watercolor & Cray-pas illustrations, undated (Box 5C:, Folder 127I)
  - Tony's Bread
    - (5) Watercolor Illustrations, undated (Box 5C:, Folder 127J)
  - What the Mailman Brought (Box 5D)
    - (5) Illustrations, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127K)
  - Mary Had a Little Lamb
    - Illustration, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127L)
  - Mary, the Mother of Jesus
    - (5) Illustrations, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127M)
  - Nicholas Bentley Stoningpot III
    - (3) Illustrations, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127N)
  - Tomie dePaola's Book of Bible Stories
    - Illustration, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127O)
  - Marianna May and Nursey
    - (5) Illustrations -transparent ink & tempera on paper, 1983 (Box 5D:, Folder 127P)
  - The Badger and the Magic Fan
    - (2) Illustrations, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127Q)
  - An Early American Christmas
    - Illustration, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127R)
  - The Miracles of Jesus
    - (2) Illustrations & sample logo-type, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127S)
  - David and Goliath
    - (8) Illustrations, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127T)
  - The Mountains of Quilt
    - (2) Illustrations, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127U)
  - My First Thanksgiving
    - (2) Illustrations, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127V)
  - The Mysterious Giant of Barletta
    - (2) Illustrations, undated (Box 5D:, Folder 127W)
  - The Hunter and the Animals
    - Illustration, undated (Box 5E:, Folder 127X)
  - Jamie O'Rourke and the Big Potato
    - (2) Illustrations (Box 5E:, Folder 127Y)
  - The Legend of the Indian Paintbrush
    - (4) Illustrations, 1988 (Box 5E:, Folder 127Z)
  - Maggie and the Monster
    - (2) Illustrations, undated (Box 5E:, Folder 128)
  - Francis, the Poor Man of Assissi
    - (4) Illustrations, undated (Box 5E:, Folder 128A)
  - The Great Adventure of Christopher Columbus
    - (17) Original Illustrations (complete book), undated (Box 5E:, Folder 128B)
  - Pages of Music
    - (3) Illustrations, 1988 (Box 5E:, Folder 128C)
  - Tomie dePaola's Mother Goose
    - (7) Illustrations -Watercolor & Tempera on paper, 1985 (Box 5E:, Folder 128D)
  - The Baby Sister
    - (19) Illustrations, ca. 1996 (Box 5E:, Folder 128E)
  - Nana Upstairs, Nana Downstairs
    - (20) Illustrations, ca. 1998 (Box 5E:, Folder 128F)
  - Illustrations / Art Work
    - “Man in Uniform” -pencil on paper, 1968 (Box 6:, Folder 130A)
    - “Moon over Kansas with cornstalk and tornado” -Pencil & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 6:, Folder 130B)
    - “Annunciation” -watercolor on paper, ca. 1965 (Box 6:, Folder 130C)
    - “Palm trees and sun” -pen and colored inks on paper, 1968 (Box 6:, Folder 130D)
    - “Moses” -pencil and watercolor on paper, 1968 (Box 6:, Folder 130E)
    - “King, Queen & Dragon” -pen & ink on paper, ca. late 1950s (Box 6:, Folder 130)
    - “The Kiss Factory in the Storm” -hand colored lithograph proof, 1968 (Box 6:, Folder 131)
    - (5) Serigraphs, undated (Box 6:, Folder 131A)
    - Lithograph proof of tree and man, undated (Box 6:, Folder 131B)
    - (6) lithograph proofs of woman, undated (Box 6:, Folder 131C)
    - (2) Photostats & Original pen & ink, 1969 (Box 6:, Folder 131D)
    - (2) Serigraphs “White Bird”, 1973 (Box 6:, Folder 131E)
    - (2) Serigraphs “Love”, undated (Box 6:, Folder 131F)
    - “The artist as a hero, about to be devoured” -pen & watercolor on paper, 1971 (Box 6:, Folder 132)
    - Collage “DFCS...” -press on type, rubber stamp on board, undated (Box 6:, Folder 133)
    - “Victorian woman in red dress” -oil on canvas panel, 1949 (Box 6:, Folder 134)
    - “Ave” -ink on coated paper, ca. mid 1960s (Box 6:, Folder 135)
    - Head of boy -oil on paper, back side: “Young St. Benedict” -tempera on paper, ca. late 1950s (Box 6:, Folder 136)
    - “Faith” -inks and Cray-pas with tempera on coated paper, ca. mid 1960s (Box 6:, Folder 137)
    - “Figure of Saint” -tempera on paper, ca. mid 1960s (Box 6:, Folder 138)
    - Peasant Woman -pen & ink & wash on watercolor paper, Back side: “Woman” -pencil, 1953 (Box 6:, Folder 139)
    - “Woman” -pen & ink & pastel on paper, ca. late 1950s (Box 6:, Folder 140)
    - “Mother and Child” -pen & ink on vellum, ca. late 1950s (Box 6:, Folder 141)
    - Sketch of two men -sanguine conte crayon on paper, undated (Box 6:, Folder 142)
    - Sketches- front & back of woman -pencil on paper, undated (Box 6:, Folder 143)
    - Sketches (6) -pencil on paper, undated (Box 6:, Folder 144)
    - Sketches, front & back -pen & ink on Bristol 1956 (Box 6:, Folder 145)
    - Sketches (7) -pencil on paper, undated (Box 6:, Folder 146)
    - Sketches (3) -pencil on paper, undated (Box 6:, Folder 147)
    - “Bird” design for card -black ink on vellum, ca. late 1950s (Box 6:, Folder 148)
    - “Christ on a cross”, back side: sketch -pencil, ca. 1960s (Box 6:, Folder 149)
    - “Saint Stephen Martyr” -watercolor & tempera, 1955 (Box 6:, Folder 150)
    - “The Brother's” -sketch, pen & ink on paper, 1957 (Box 6:, Folder 151)
    - Sketch of building -pen & ink on paper, ca. late 1950s (Box 6:, Folder 152)
    - Paper collage -paint on illustration board, ca. mid 1960s (Box 6:, Folder 153)
    - Paper collage -Cray-pas, paint on illustration board, ca. mid 1960s (Box 6:, Folder 154)
    - “Baby” -pen & ink & watercolor inks on paper, ca. late 1950s (Box 6:, Folder 155)
    - “Mary” -watercolor & poster paint on paper, ca. late 1940s (Box 6:, Folder 156)
    - “Madonna and Child” -tempera on paper, ca. mid 1950s (Box 6:, Folder 157)
    - “The Richest of the Poor” -seperations, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 6:, Folder 158)
    - “Times Square” -wash-out, black & white & gray, 1953-1954 (Box 6:, Folder 159)
  - Oversized (Box 7)
    - “Giovanna Clorinda de Pestollo was baptized...” pen & watercolor on paper, 1978 (Box 7:, Folder 159A)
    - Forest landscape -tempera & ink on paper, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 159B)
    - Bologna Children's Book Fair poster -watercolor, Rubber stamp, pen & ink on paper, ca. 1980 (Box 7:, Folder 159C)
    - 3 Lithograph prints, undated (Box 7:, Folder 159D)
    - “Hamlet” -ink and colored inks on paper, 1969 (Box 7:, Folder 160)
    - “Macbeth” -ink and colored inks on paper, 1969 (Box 7:, Folder 161)
    - “The Tempest” -ink and colored inks on paper, 1969 (Box 7:, Folder 162)
    - “As You Like It” -ink and colored inks on paper, 1969 (Box 7:, Folder 163)
    - “Romeo and Juliet” -ink and colored inks on paper, 1969 (Box 7:, Folder 164)
    - Set design for show curtain at Colby-Sawyer College -marker on illustration board, undated (Box 7:, Folder 165)
    - Original drawings for The Morning Glory -pen & ink on paper, pp. 12, 18, and 10, 1969 (Box 7:, Folder 166)
    - “White Bird” -serigraph, undated (Box 7:, Folder 167)
    - “Cousin Kitty, Flossie & Tom” -ink & tempera on pastel paper, 1965 (Box 7:, Folder 168)
    - “Oh, Say Can You See” -ink wash on paper, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 169)
    - “Skowhegan, Maine” -unfinished oil study, 1955 (Box 7:, Folder 170)
    - “Poppies” -ink tempera on paper, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 171)
    - “Settings for a Romantic Play Act One” -ink & colored ink on paper, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 172)
    - “Bird” -Serigraph on paper, ca. 1960s (Box 7:, Folder 173)
    - “God” -ink and collage on paper, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 174)
    - “Poster for Cannolis” -pencil, ink, Cray-pas & tempera on paper, 1966 (Box 7:, Folder 175)
    - “Virgin with Heart” -pen & ink & Cray-pas on paper, 1965 (Box 7:, Folder 176)
    - “Rapunzel” -colored inks on paper, ca. 1960 (Box 7:, Folder 177)
    - “California USA” -tempera on paper, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 178)
    - “Bride” -pen & ink & Cray-pas on paper, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 179)
    - “The Fruit was Picked...” -pencil on paper, 1976 (Box 7:, Folder 180)
    - “The Amphora of Creation” -pencil & watercolor on paper, 1972 (Box 7:, Folder 181)
  - New Yorker Cover Designs (Box 8)
    - “Kiss Factory” -pencil & watercolor on paper, ca. 1972 (Box 8:, Folder 182)
    - “City with Comets” -pencil & watercolor on paper, ca. 1972 (Box 8:, Folder 183)
    - Man on rooftop -pen & watercolor on paper, ca. 1972 (Box 8:, Folder 184)
    - “Santa Claus” -pencil & watercolor on paper, ca. 1972 (Box 8:, Folder 185)
    - Man walking dog... -pen & watercolor on paper, ca. 1972 (Box 8:, Folder 186)
    - Baby & bunny -pen & watercolor on paper, ca. 1972 (Box 8:, Folder 187)
    - Woman at Vegetable Stand -pen & watercolor, ca. 1972 (Box 8:, Folder 188)
  - Costume Sketches
    - “Wall Street Rag” -marker on paper, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 189)
    - “Magyarettes” -marker on paper, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 190)
    - “Lady in Red” -marker & pencil on paper, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 191)
    - “Artist” -marker & pen on paper, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 192)
    - “Can-Can Girls” -marker & pen on paper, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 193)
  - Costume Sketches for She Stoops to Conquer
    - “Sir Charles” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1973 (Box 8:, Folder 194A)
    - “Bet” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1973 (Box 8:, Folder 194)
    - “Three Women” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1973 (Box 8:, Folder 195)
    - “Kate Hardcastle” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1973 (Box 8:, Folder 196)
    - “Tony Lumpkin” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1973 (Box 8:, Folder 197)
    - “Constance Neville” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1973 (Box 8:, Folder 198)
    - “Mrs. Hardcastle” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1973 (Box 8:, Folder 199)
    - “3 children & 2 men” -marker & pen & ink on paper, 1973 (Box 8:, Folder 200)
    - Cabaret- “Kit Kat Club Girls” costume sketch -colored pencil & tempera on cardboard, ca. mid 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 201)
    - Cabaret- “Kit Kat Club Girls” costume sketch -colored pencil & tempera on cardboard, ca. mid 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 201A)
    - Cabaret - Fraulein Kost costume sketch -colored pencil & tempera on cardboard, ca. mid 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 201B)
    - Cabaret- “Sitting Pretty” & “If You Could See Her” -colored pencil & tempera on cardboard, ca. mid 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 201C)
    - Cabaret - Sally Bowles costume sketch -colored pencil & tempera on cardboard, ca. mid 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 201D)
    - Cabaret - Frau Schneider costume sketch -colored pencil & tempera on cardboard, ca. mid 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 201E)
    - Cabaret - Two ladies & M/C costume sketch -colored pencil & tempera on cardboard, ca. mid 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 201F)
    - Cabaret - Sally Bowles Mama costume sketch -colored pencil & tempera on cardboard, ca. mid 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 201G)
    - Rags - Dance concert costume sketch -colored markers on paper, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 202)
  - Art Work done at Pratt
    - “A Variation of the Fifth Floor Lobby” -watercolor on paper, 1952 (Box 9:, Folder 202A)
    - “Peter and the Wolf” -tempera on paper, 1952 (Box 9:, Folder 202B)
    - “Color problem: Cool Iced Tea” -tempera on board, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 203)
    - “Mother and Child” -pen & ink on Bristol board Back side: sketch, ca. 1952-1954 (Box 9:, Folder 204)
    - “The Five Wise Virgins” -watercolor and tempera, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 205)
    - “Souvenirs” -watercolor & tempera on paper, ca. 1953-1954 (Box 9:, Folder 206)
    - “Circus Project” -casein on masonite panel, 1952 (Box 9:, Folder 207)
    - Figure Study: two people -pen & ink, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 208)
    - “Old Testament Woman” -Cray-pas on board, ca. 1963-1964 (Box 9:, Folder 209)
    - Figure Study: woman seated -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 210)
    - “Tomie dePaola as drawn by Calvin Albert” -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 211)
    - Figure Study: back view of man standing -charcoal, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 212)
    - Figure Study: woman standing -sanguine conte crayon on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 213)
    - Figure Study -brown conte crayon on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 214)
    - Figure Study: Woman in blue -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 215)
    - Figure Study -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 216)
    - Figure Study: side view of man standing -charcoal and pastel on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 217)
    - Figure Study: woman standing -pen & ink, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 218)
    - Figure Study: two women sitting -charcoal & pastel, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 219)
    - Figure Study: back view of woman sitting -charcoal, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 220)
    - Figure Study: woman standing -charcoal, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 221)
    - Figure Study: man standing, man sitting -charcoal, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 222)
    - Figure Study -charcoal on paper, ca. 1952-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 223)